Guillermo Garcia Saldierna

ggarciasaldierna@nevada.unr.edu | (775) 338-0472 | 1580 Sutro St, Reno, NV 89512

SUMMARY

Computer science and engineering graduate focusing on software and hardware maintenance with quality control. Adept in developing software written in C++, C#, and JavaScript with excellence troubleshooting and debugging proficiency. Experienced in software installation and network configuration. Self-starter that is able to adapt quickly to changing work environment and stay up-to-date with emerging technology.

SKILLS

Operation Systems: Windows OS, Ubuntu Linux, Android

Software: VMWare, MATLAB, Visual Studios, Xamarin, GitHub, Unity, Microsoft Office

Programming: Unix-like command prompts, C/C++/C#, JavaScript, JQuery, HTM5L, CSS, OpenGL, Python, XML **Other Skills**: Exceptional at troubleshooting and diagnostic, communication and relation skills, bilingual

EDUCATION

University of Nevada, Reno, Reno, NV

August 2012 – December 2017

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering. GPA: 3.277

Minor in Mathematics

Relevant Courses:

Data Structures Embedded Systems Design Computer Communication Networks
Operating Systems Internet Programming I Advance Business Systems Development

EXPERIENCE

Assembler II, International Game Technology – Reno, NV

July 2018 – Present

- In constant communication with a production team to ensure that the assembly of gaming machines are built with precision and punctually
- Proficient in various phases of the production line which allows me to assist my team where needed
- Adept in numerous different builds of lottery machines that has made me flexible with the dynamics of the day-to-day operations
- Trained as the department coordinator to cover if needed; which includes, communicating with different department heads, ensured daily goals are met, filled-out reports pertaining to missing items and dysfunctional parts.

Material Handler II (AppleOne), International Game Technology – Reno, NV

April 2018 – July 2018

- Inspected equipment ensuring that warehouse products are handled with care
- Organized kits to guarantee the accuracy and fluidity of production
- Accountable for delivering gaming parts in a timely manner throughout different departments within the company campus

Substitute Teacher, Washoe County School District – Reno, NV

February 2018 – April 2018

- Adapting to different classroom environments with varying class sizes and grade levels ranging from K-12
- Followed the teacher's lesson plans while engaging in optimal learning and ensuring student engagement
- Responsible for filling out end-of-day reports and ensuring student well-being

Instructor, NCLab – Reno, NV

August 2014 – August 2015

- Taught low-level programming and 3-D modeling/design, derived from Python and JavaScript, in a computer lab to elementary students
- Coached students to use critical thinking methods and helped develop problem solving skills
- Consulted with parents regarding their children's progress
- Regulated a class ranging between ten to thirty students

LEADERSHIP

Omega Delta Phi Inc., Beta Delta Chapter, President-Elect – Reno, NV

January 2017 – August 2017

- Leadership position in which constant communication and supervision between the members was a must
- Organized and delegated events including fundraiser, meetings, and formal banquets
- Filed paperwork and oversaw that deadlines were met accordingly within the organization